An offer you can't refuse.
The Godfather is a drama, crime film directed by Francis Ford Coppola.
Spanning the years 1945 to 1955, a chronicle of the
fictional Italian-American Corleone crime family.
When organized crime family patriarch, Vito Corleone barely survives an attempt on his life, his youngest son,
Michael steps in to take care of the would-be killers, launching a campaign of bloody revenge.
Don Vito Corleone, played by Marlon Brando.
Michael Corleone, played by Al Pacino.
Sonny Corleone, played by James Caan.
Tom Hagen, played by Robert Duvall.
Clemenza, played by Richard S. Castellano.
Kay Adams, played by Diane Keaton.
The Godfather is a 1972 American epic gangster film directed by Francis Ford Coppola, who
co-wrote the screenplay with Mario Puzo based on Puzo's best-selling 1969 novel.
The film features an ensemble cast that includes Marlon Brando, Al Pacino, James Caan, Richard
Castellano, Robert Duvall, Sterling Hayden, John Marley, Richard Conte and Diane Keaton.
It is the first installment in The Godfather trilogy, which chronicles the Corleone family under patriarch Vito Corleone (Brando) and
the transformation of his youngest son, Michael Corleone (Pacino), from reluctant family outsider to ruthless mafia boss.
Paramount Pictures obtained the rights to the novel for
$80,000, before it gained popularity.
Studio executives had trouble finding a director; the first few candidates turned down the position before Coppola signed on to direct
the film, but disagreement followed over casting several characters, in particular Vito (Brando) and Michael (Pacino).
Filming took place primarily in locations around New York City and
Sicily, and it was completed ahead of schedule.
The score was composed principally by Nino Rota, with
additional pieces by Carmine Coppola.
The Godfather premiered at the Loew's State Theatre on March 14, 1972, and
was widely released in the United States on March 24, 1972.
It was the highest-grossing film of 1972, and was for a time the highest-grossing film
ever made, earning between $250 and $291 million at the box office.
The film was acclaimed by critics and audiences, who praised its performances—particularly those of Brando and
Pacino—direction, screenplay, story, cinematography, editing, score, and portrayal of the mafia.
The Godfather launched the successful careers of Coppola, Pacino,
and other relative newcomers in the cast and crew.
At the 45th Academy Awards, the film won Best Picture, Best Actor
(Brando), and Best Adapted Screenplay (for Puzo and Coppola).
In addition, the seven other Oscar nominations included Pacino, Caan, and
Duvall, all for Best Supporting Actor, and Coppola for Best Director.
The Godfather is regarded as one of the greatest and most influential
films ever made, as well as a landmark of the gangster genre.
It was selected for preservation in the U.S.
National Film Registry of the Library of Congress in 1990, being deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant"
and is ranked the second-greatest film in American cinema (behind Citizen Kane) by the American Film Institute.
It was followed by sequels The Godfather Part II
(1974) and The Godfather Part III (1990).
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, loss of
loved one, love at first sight, italy, gangster.
The tone is emotional.